Once upon a time, there was a princess who was held captive.
She was imprisoned in the Demon King's castle, her freedom taken from her.
The princess had no choice but to dance like a puppet to the tune set by the whims of her sadistic captor.
One day, a hero came to fight the Demon King, seeking to save the princess.
However, there was no way the hero could attain the victory.
For you see, the hero did not know that he himself was a puppet that the Demon King had created.
Vakir!
Tutu!
Where am I?
Gears?
Why are they all stopped?
What am I doing?
In a place like this?
What should I do now?
Vakir!
Drosselmeyer.
The man who toys with everyone's fates.
Is he out there somewhere, laughing as he watches her and Muto suffer?
Where is she right now?
Is she where Drosselmeyer is?
Where the hell is that?
By now this story may have progressed to the point where we can do nothing.
In that case, the only one who can fight is he who carries the same blood!
You mean, I should write then?
There's no other way that I'll be able to save her at this point.
Where is the exit?
I must leave this place.
I know where they are.
The other heart shards are in the five gates around the town.
I must return them to Muto soon.
And then Muto will return to the story.
And I'll go back to being...
A duck.
Shhh!
What's this?
A puppet?
Yes, that's right!
You're in the puppet world now!
Who's this?
You're Princess Tootoo, aren't you?
It's Tootoo!
We wonder what Tootoo is tootoo!
Do you know where this place is?
Please tell me!
Why was I brought here?
Was there some reason?
Why has everything in this place just stopped?
That's rather irresponsible of you, wouldn't you say?
Not knowing where you are?
Then please, tell me!
Tootoo says she wants us to tell her!
This is Tootoo in a pickle!
A pickle!
Enter me!
You're the one who stopped everything, Princess Tootoo!
Didn't you know?
This is the inside of the story!
And you're the one who caused the story to stop!
Caused the story to stop?
I did it?
That's right!
Tootoo stopped the story!
Tootoo stopped all the gears!
She stopped them!
Tootoo stopped them!
Stop it!
My body!
It won't move!
Hear the voice which is voiceless,
and see the shape which is shapeless.
What am I supposed to do with that?
What should I write?
Damn it!
I have to write!
Where is the heart?
Daughter, hurry up and fetch me a heart!
Dear father, now that I have gone and dyed the prince's heart in your blood, he'll definitely become mine, right father?
Are you saying you cannot trust what I tell you?
Oh no!
Of course not!
And you think, on top of that, you only consider yourself and not me!
Your father?
That's not true!
I love you, father, but...
It's only natural for a daughter to love her father!
And you think, on top of that, you only consider yourself and not me, your father!
That's not true!
I love you, father, but...
It's only natural for a daughter to love her father!
You're pathetic!
Pathetic. To think you can't even get the love of the prince in the story.
At this point, you no longer have any value to me as a daughter.
Father!
You should at least give me your heart, so that I might be restored to some degree, however small.
Father! Forgive me, I'm sorry!
I have not given you leave, Prey!
Have I turned into a puppet?
Did I do something bad? Is that why?
Is that...
Uzura!
I found Tutu, Zura!
What are you doing here, Uzura?
I followed you, Zura. What are you doing, Zura?
I think I've somehow turned into a puppet.
A puppet, Zura?
It's not that I don't like being a puppet, it's just...
Uzura!
A puppet, Zura?
Je t'ai entrelacé.
My feet are moving on their own.
Pretty long de jambes, Antoineau.
Mr. Drosselmeyer? Is this the world where Mr. Drosselmeyer is?
How? Why? I'm just a marionette dancing exactly as I'm told. I don't like this. I want to dance more... more freely.
Such thinking is mistaken.
Marionettes are their most free when they're being manipulated by their strings. You won't be able to leave this place unless you acknowledge that.
What's a puppet, Zura?
Well, her name is Uzura. Karin, he made her from the wood from Edel that didn't burn up.
From Miss Edel?
Does that mean I'm not Uzra, Zura?
Huh?
Oh!
What's this, Zura?
Oh! It hurts, Zura!
Oh!
It hurts, Zura!
Call, call!
Hello, Krehi. Come here, won't you?
My prince?
Come, come now. Why the hunted look?
Let's enjoy ourselves.
I want to get all my feelings back, the sooner the better.
Once that's taken care of, I can give the raven my heart.
What are you saying? That's a joke, right?
The prince is fated to marry no one but me.
Marry you?
You who, in spite of your being a crow, have that ugly human body.
That's the joke.
The only thing that you are allowed to do is love me.
The moment you died, you'll have to love me.
You died my heart with raven's blood.
Our fates were immediately sealed.
But I did just what father told me to.
Then I'd rather just take his heart out again.
But I don't have the prince's sword.
If I thrust this sword into the prince, he might die.
That's fine.
If that happens, I too will...
I have one last favor to ask.
After you've ripped out my heart,
I want you to kiss it and dye your lips crimson with my blood.
What's the matter?
Can't you do it?
Well, looks like you've reached your limit.
I'll admit, picking Drosselmeyer's grave to write at was pretty sharp for you.
But if the words you should be writing aren't coming to you without even having to think...
Could you please be a little quieter?
And think.
At this moment, I have volumes upon volumes that I want to write.
It's ironic.
Faster.
I've got to write faster.
Good grief.
You'd be better off letting the story pull you along like a good boy.
Well, it's of no real consequence.
You needn't fret, little duck.
I'll be coming for you soon.
Who's there?
Welcome to this quaint little gap in time, my dear Princess Tutu.
Mr. Drosselmeyer.
So, what did those puppets mean when they told me I stopped the story?
I'm just...
trying my best to completely return the prince's heart to it.
Tell me, have you discovered all the locations of the scattered heart, Charles?
What?
Um, I'm not quite sure, but I think that they're hidden in the five gates around the town.
My congratulations to you.
What?
So if I return those five shards to him, the prince will go back to normal and defeat the raven and then...
No, no, no.
That would be hopelessly boring.
You're a story character.
You can do better than that.
Character?
But how can that be?
I'm really only a duck.
Correct.
But you're inside the story right now.
Everybody is.
Take a look.
Rue.
Fuck here.
Mewtwo.
Everyone's suffering, you see.
This is the way it has to be.
Tutu has something she should suffer over, too.
The choice to confess her love and immediately vanish,
or never to confess her love and thereby forever lose the prince.
Never mind that.
And yet to think, returning the prince to normal is more important to you than your own problems.
You're a much different duck now than the one you once were who so desired was for the prince.
You should be desperately in love with the prince and want to marry him.
Am I wrong?
I just...
That's right.
You shouldn't fight what's natural.
It's only natural to want to make the prince yours and yours alone.
There's nothing to be shamed of.
I know.
How does this idea appeal to your nature?
Simply pretend you haven't realized that the remaining heart shards are hidden in the five gates.
What?
After all, nobody else has realized.
So if you do that, there will be nothing to part you from the prince.
That...
My dear duck, if you can't think, at least on that level, you'll never leave here.
And the story will stay stopped, too.
What's this?
Tutu is here and yet the gears are moving.
What is going on?
Oh, no.
Interesting.
The gears are starting to turn backwards.
The story will now double back on itself.
What?
I never once envisioned something like this.
How intriguing.
I wonder what will happen.
I don't understand anymore.
I believe that my marriage to the prince was the fate the story had decided for us.
Was I wrong?
What should I believe?
Whom should I believe?
I want to go back to that time before I remembered everything.
That time when I was Rue.
Help me!
I'm sorry, father.
Don't take my heart.
Forgive me.
That was...
Help me a good girl.
Oh!
Get behind me.
That's the prince.
Back when I first met him.
You don't have to worry anymore.
Does it hurt?
I brought water.
Thank you.
I have to go.
Go where?
Back home to my father.
Who are you?
My name is...
My pitiful daughter, who despite being a crow, has been born into an ugly human body.
I'm... I'm not a crow.
I'm a... a person.
I'm...
C...
R...
My name is Rue.
Can I come see you again?
Yes.
Goodbye.
What's going on?
The story's flowing backwards.
What?
Stop it.
Hurry and stop it with your pin.
Here.
The story's doubling back?
I've experienced a lot of new feelings since becoming a human girl.
In the beginning, I didn't think my feelings for Mewtwo would grow so much.
I will never go back.
Not to that time when I clung to my sword and said nothing but words that deprived Mewtwo of his freedom.
All of my feelings belong to me.
All feelings are precious to whom they belong.
And I am nobody's marionette.
I will no longer cower before fate.
Whatever it takes.
We'll guard him.
Together.
Just now, I heard her voice.
That's right.
She's changed me.
I can write.
I can write a story about her.
But wait.
These words, they're not my words.
What are they?
Everything stopped moving, Zora.
The story doesn't want to go back any more than that.
Who's that, Zora?
Are you a puppet, Zora?
I am a puppet.
And I am you.
You are also me.
I'm not Usra, Zora?
I am a puppet who could not have a heart.
But you.
Now go back to where Duck is.
Wait, Zora!
These are all her feelings.
I want to go back.
I want to go back and help Muto.
I want to leave this place.
Her feelings for Muto are spilling up through my hand and out onto the page.
And that time, the knight who had cast away his sword called her name
in order to lead her out of the darkness.
Duck!
Look here!
There.
Go on.
Duck!
suggestion!
not to be underestimated.
And thanks to this, the story is still stopped.
Hmm?
Oh, it would appear that there is one
who is still doubling back.
You're going to find out something you wish you hadn't.
Now, where am I?
What's wrong?
My daughter's been kidnapped by the crows!
What?
We'll start searching over there.
Thank you.
That there, that's me?
Then I, after all this, I'm not the Raven's daughter.
I had a mother.
I had a father.
I'm a normal human being.
What a wretched faint.
Yes!
Hmm?
The stories finally started moving.
My, my.
Thank goodness.
Oh, so that means I'm not Uhtra Sora?
My heart isn't lovey-dovey Sora?
Where am I Sora?
OOOH!
OOOOOOH!
I'm a PY, Sora!
My love has done nothing but make you into this.
I have no right to love you.
Duck doesn't know. There's a thing she doesn't know.
Just now, I was afraid of Mewto.
Even if I put water on you, you won't change back, Soda?
That's why I'm asking for your help, Altor.
So this is the raven?
This frail earnest love. I must protect this love.
All you children who love stories, come gather round.
Thank you.